Nowicki, Joseph; Papers apap266
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Nowicki, Joseph Papers
Undated
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Nowicki, Joseph F. X.
apap266
12 cubic ft.
This collection documents the service of Joseph F. X. Nowicki of Pearl River, NY in the New York State Assembly representing Rockland County from 1961 through 1964.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Joseph F. X. Nowicki initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in 1965. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
Assemblyman Joseph F. X. Nowicki, was born in Yonkers on October 18, 1922. Nowicki enlisted in the U.S. Marine Corps in March 1942, and was commissioned as a second lieutenant on September 30, 1944. After his service, he returned to Fordham College and graduated in 1947 and then from Fordham Law School in 1950. He served again from 1950-1952 in Korea, discharged with the rank of captain.
Joseph Nowicki was one of the founding members and first president of the Rockland County Young Republican Club. During 1959 and 1960, Nowicki was counsel to New York's Lieutenant Governor Malcolm Wilson. In 1960, he was elected to the New York Assembly in the general election for Rockland County. His committee assignments included City of New York Claims, Excise, General Laws, Judiciary, Public Service, and Joint Legislative Committee on Municipal Tort Liability of which he was vice-chairman. He served in the Assembly until 1964. He died of cancer on April 23, 1976 at the age of 53, leaving his wife, Catherine; five sons, Joseph, Peter, Paul, Michael and Patrick; two daughters, Catherine and Ann; his mother, Mrs. Joseph A. Nowicki; two sisters, and a brother.
Scope and Contents
The Joseph Nowicki Papers span the years of 1954-1964 and are related to his career as a member of the Republican party and as a New York State Assemblyman. The papers include Assembly bills and supporting materials, correspondence, and subject files. These materials represent his activities in the Republican Party and as a legislator.
The types of materials contain but are not limited to: bills, newspaper clippings, telegrams, reports, memos, maps, pictures, notes, and bound copies of bills.
The series arrangement reflect the way that Nowicki and his staff organized and filed his papers. The archivist also elected to retain the original folder titles.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: Series 1 - Subject Files; Series 2 - Legislation; and Series 3 - General Correspondence. Series 1 is arranged alphabetically while Series 2 and 3 are chronological.
New York (State)—Politics and government; Politics and Politicians; Public Servants; Legislation (legal concepts); Files by subject; Correspondence.
- Subject Files, 1954-1964; 1; 6.2 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the general subject files of Assemblyman Joseph Nowicki’s office, including letters, memos, newsletters, press releases, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, transcripts, reports, informational booklets, notes, original legislation, resolutions, petitions, statements, maps, photographs, and constituent correspondence.
  Researchers will find that a number of these subject files relate to Nowicki Assembly committee work, legislation, and the Republican Party. Nowicki served as vice-chairman of the Joint Legislative Committee on Municipal Tort Liability Committee and a large part of the material will pertain to claims and annexations within New York City. Included in this series are also general proposed pieces of legislation from other Assembly Committees.
  - AFL-CIO Newsletters, 1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aging, 1960; 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aging Information, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aging Memos and Information, 1959; 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agriculture, 1960-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agriculture Information, Memos, and Bill, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alcohol (1 of 2), 1963-1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alcohol (2 of 2), 1963-1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alcoholic Beverages, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annexations: Spring Valley, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Annual Report, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Auto Fee Increase (1 of 2), 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Auto Fee Increase (2 of 2), 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Banks, 1962-1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Banks Memos and Correspondence, 1961-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Biography, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Boxing, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pete Bradley, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Budget, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Budget (1 of 2), 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Budget (2 of 2), 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Budget, 1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Budget Memos and Information, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Builders, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Builders, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Capital Punishment, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Capital Punishment Information and Memos, 1959; 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Speaker Carlino, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Chamber of Commerce, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Chiropractor's License Correspondence, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Chiropractors, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - City of NY Committee, 1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - City of NY Economic Development (1 of 2), 1960-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - City of NY Economic Development (2 of 2), 1960-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - City of NY Memos, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Civil Practice, 1961; 1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Civil Practice Memos, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Civil Rights, 1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Civil Service, 1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Civil Service Memos, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Civil Service News, 1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Claims, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Condon-Wadlin Law, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Conservation Law, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conservation Law, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Conservation Law, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Constitutional Revision, 1961-1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Court Reorganization, 1960; 1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Court Reorganization, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dairy, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Diefendorf Committee, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Discrimination, 1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Disturbed Children, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Disturbed Children, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Drug Safety Act, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Duplicate Memos, 1960; Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - East Hudson Parkway Authority, 1960-1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Election Law, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Election Law, 1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Equalization Rates, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Excise, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Excise Committee, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Excise Committee, 1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Fallout Shelter Report, 1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Federal Government, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Firearms, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Fireman, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Fireman, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Full Crew, 1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - General Laws, 1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - General Laws Committee, 1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - General Laws Committee, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Governor, 1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Hammarskjold, 1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Health, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Health, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Higher Education (1 of 2), 1960-1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Higher Education (2 of 2), 1960-1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Higher Education, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Higher Education, 1961-1963; Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Higher Education, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Highways, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Highways, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Highways, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Home Builders, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Hospitals, 1963; Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Housing, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Housing, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Housing, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Human Rights, 1962-1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Humane Slaughter, 1960-1962; Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Humane Slaughter, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Insurance, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Insurance, 1963; Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Insurance Agents, 1961; Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on Municipal Tort Liability (1 of 2), 1962-1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on Municipal Tort Liability (2 of 2), 1962-1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Judicial Conference, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Judicial Conference, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Judiciary (1 of 2), 1963; Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Judiciary (2 of 2), 1963; Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Judiciary Committee (1 of 2), 1963-1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Judiciary Committee (2 of 2), 1963-1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Kennedy, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - (Coffee) Klatches, 1960; Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Korean Bonus, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Labor, 1960-1962; Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Labor (1 of 2), 1962-1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Labor (2 of 2), 1962-1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Legislation, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Legislation, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Legislative Library, 1962-1964; Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Legislative Program, 1960-1962; Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Legislature, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Liberal Party, 1961; Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mental Health, 1962; Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Milk, 1962; Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Minimum Wage Law, 1961; Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Newsletters (1 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Newsletters (1 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Moreland Letters, 1964; Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Motor Vehicle, 1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Motor Vehicle, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Motor Vehicle, Undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - New York City, 1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - New York State, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - New York State Bar Association, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - New York State Employees, 1961; 1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - NYS Moreland Commission (1 of 2), 1963-1964; Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - NYS Moreland Commission (2 of 2), 1963-1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Clarence Noyes, 1960-1962; Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Clarence Noyes, 1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Nurses, 1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Obscene Materials, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Off Track Betting, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Opticians, 1960-1962; Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Penal Law, 1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Penal Law, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Penal Law and Crime, 1960; 1962; Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Per Capital Aid, Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - PPR (Permanent Personal Registration), 1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Press Releases, 1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, 1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Public Health, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Public Service, 1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Public Service Committee, 1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Racing, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Railroads, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Railroads, 1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Recreational Park Bond, 1960; Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Releases, 1958-1959; Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Rent Control, 1959-1962; Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Republican Party, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Residence Laws, 1959-1960; Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Resolution 790, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Retirement--Alice S. Humeston, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Gov. Rockefeller, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Roll Calls, 1958; Undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Rose Festival, 1954-1955; 1960 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Rose Festival, 1955; Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Route 104 Problems, 1957-1960; Undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Sabbath Law, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Sabbath Law (1 of 2), 1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Sabbath Law (2 of 2), 1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Sane, 1961-1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Scholar Incentive, 1961; Undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Scholarships, 1962; Undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Scholarships, 1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - School Aid (1 of 4), 1961-1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - School Aid (2 of 4), 1961-1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - School Aid (3 of 4), 1961-1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - School Aid (4 of 4), 1961-1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Social Welfare, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Speno-Brennan Transportation Law, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - State Aid, 1963; Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - State Aid, 15%, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - State Employees Pay Raise, 1960-1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - State Spending, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Stony Point Haverstraw, 1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Suburban Town Law, 1963; Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Taxes, 1960-1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Taxes, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Teachers, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Teachers, 1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Testimony from Railroad Association Testimony (1 of 3), 1960; 1962-1964; Undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Testimony from Railroad Association Testimony (2 of 3), 1960; 1962-1964; Undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Testimony from Railroad Association Testimony (3 of 3), 1960; 1962-1964; Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Thruway Authority, 1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Transportation, 1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Transportation, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Tuition Letters, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Unemployment, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Unemployment, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Unemployment Insurance, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Unemployment Insurance, 1964; Undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Veterans, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Veterans, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Welfare, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Welfare, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - World's Fair, 1964; Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Youth, 1960; 1962; Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Youth, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Youth Employment Service (1 of 2), 1961-1962; Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Youth Employment Service (2 of 2), 1961-1962; Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Legislation, 1960-1964; 2; 1.6 cubic ft.
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series contains legislation introduced by Assemblyman Joseph Nowicki, and supporting materials including related correspondence and newspaper clippings. The series also includes statute books that Nowicki kept for reference.
  Note that in 1963 there are bills labeled “AP” and this indicates a bill was drafted, but not put on that year’s docket for a vote.
  - Print 4084, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Print 438, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Print 3184, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Print 2916, 1960-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Assembly Bills: Public Service, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Print 1401, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Print 2129, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Print 2557, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Print 3204, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Print 3634, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Print 3635, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Print 3765, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Print 3946, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Print 4278, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Print 4279, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Print 4578, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Print 4678, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Print 4844, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Print 4845, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Print 5260, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Public Housing Law, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Print 2507, 1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Print 3203, 1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Print 3944, 1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Print 3945, 1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Print 4679, 1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Print 4842, 1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Print 4843, 1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Print 4925, 1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Print 5049, 1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Print 263, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Print 322, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Print 467, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Print 1172, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Print 1532, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Print 1541, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Print 2889, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Print 1036, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Print 1531, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Print 1854, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Print 1855, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Print 2325, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Print 3951, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Print 4844, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Print 1058, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Print 1059, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Print 1061, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Print 1102, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Print 1249, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Print 2978, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Print 3265, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Print 5177, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Press Releases, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Print 1060, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Print 1171, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Print 1922, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Print 2493, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Print 3045, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Print 3264, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Print 3266, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Print 3428, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Print 3538, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Print 3539, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Print 3948, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Print 3949, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Print 3950, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Print 4594, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Print 379, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Print 380, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - AP 3214, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Print 230, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Print 381, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Print 978, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Print 979, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Print 1479, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Print 1794, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Print 2990, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Print 5761, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - New York City, 1962-1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Print 153, 1962-1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Print 3204, 1962-1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - AP 3213, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Print 3948, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Assembly Bills: General Laws, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Print 282, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Print 284, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Print 285, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Print 378, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Print 2991, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Print 2992, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Print 3679, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Stony Point Volunteer Fireman, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - AP 3676, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - AP 3677, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - AP 3678, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - AP 3680, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - AP 4506, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - AP 4556, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - AP 4557, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Print 152, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Print 286, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Print 1478, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Print 1480, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Print 1793, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Print 1957, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Print 2231, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Print 2241, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Print 5662, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Print 5763, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Stony Point Volunteer Fireman, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Print 177, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Print 4225, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Labor, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Print 151, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Print 178, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pirnt 179, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Print 180, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Print 1272, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Print 1373, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Print 1696, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Print 2253, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Print 3273, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Print 4867, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Assembly Bills: City of New York (1 of 3), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Assembly Bills: City of New York (2 of 3), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Assembly Bills: City of New York (3 of 3), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Print 149, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Print 181, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Print 2255, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Print 3272, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Print 4095, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Print 4714, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Print 148, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Print 150, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Print 182, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Print 867, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Print 3202, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Print 3203, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Print 3271, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Print 3274, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Print 3979, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Print 4713, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Print 4733, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Print 5166, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Print 6044, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- General Correspondence, 1959-1964; 3; 2.0 cubic ft.
  Each year of this general correspondence file is arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains correspondence related to the legislative activities of Assemblyman Joseph Nowicki, constituent matters, and interest groups.
  The archivist retained the original order of the materials. Researchers should therefore note that there are letters addressed to Nowicki that may appear to be out of alphabetical order. It is likely that the staff kept these other letters as reference materials for they involve similar issues as the ones in alphabetical order.
  - 1961 A (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1961 B, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1961 C, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1961 D, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1961 E, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1961 F, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1961 G, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1961 H, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1961 I, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1961 J, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1961 K, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1961 L, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1961 M, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1961 N, 1960; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1962 A, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)